Guide to the Property Plats Collection, Circa 1925-1932 UA.10.05.0005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Property Plats
circa 1925-1932
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke Construction Company
UA.10.05.0005
6.0 Linear Feet
Although the exact provenance of the property plats is unknown, it is indicated on the reverse side of some plats that the surveys were used by A. C. Lee, Chief Engineer of the Duke Construction Company and the plats may have been created by the Atlantic Realty Company. This collection includes approximately 100 survey plats of Duke University properties prior to the construction on East Campus and West Campus from the years 1925-1926. Also included are plats representing the Duke Homestead from 1932 that were possibly drawn by V.A. Stewman.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Property Plats were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1979.
Collection Overview
This collection includes approximately 100 survey plats of Duke University properties prior to the construction on East Campus and West Campus from the years 1925-1926. Some plats represent part of what is now Duke Forest. The plats show details of the topography and terrain, roads and streets, bodies of water, trees and buildings. A key map is included. On the reverse side of some plats, it is indicated that the surveys were used by A. C. Lee, Chief Engineer of the Duke Construction Company and the plats may have been produced by the Atlantic Realty Company. Also included are plats representing the Duke Homestead from 1932 that were possibly drawn by V.A. Stewman. Topics include Duke Construction Company, East Campus, West Campus, Duke Forest and the Duke Homestead.
Drawings are pen and pencil on paper mounted to cloth, measuring approximately 23"x30", organized according to geographic locations The scale is approximately 50 feet to the inch.
Plats (maps); Duke University -- West Campus; Duke University -- East Campus; Duke Homestead (Durham, N.C.); Duke Forest (N.C.) -- Maps; Duke Construction Company
- Property Plats, circa 1925-1932, 19 Oversize Folders, 1 Oversize Box
  Scope and Contents note
  The individual plats can be assembled to show all of East and West Campuses, and there is a key which shows how the plats fit together. On the key, plats are organized by section number. Likewise, plats listed below are grouped by section.
  - East Campus and key, circa 1925-1926 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Section 1
  - Central and West Campus, circa 1925-1926; 3 folders (Box 1)
    Section 2
  - West Campus, circa 1925-1926; 3 folders (Box 2)
    Section 3
  - West Campus, circa 1925-1926; 3 folders (Box 2)
    Section 4.
  - West Campus, circa 1925-1926, 3 folders (Box 4)
    Section 5.
  - Duke Forest, circa 1925-1926; 2 folders (Box 3)
    This area not located on map key.
  - Duke Forest, circa 1925-1926; 2 folders (Box 3)
    Section 6.
  - Duke Homestead Plats, 1932 (Box 4)
  - Duke Forest, Durham Division, 1925, 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Property Plats and Key, copy 2, circa 1925-1926 (Box 5)